paytrace.com 2014-07-02

# PayTrace.com | Privacy Policy

### Privacy Statement for PayTrace

Because PayTrace takes privacy and data protection issues seriously, we have designed this Privacy Policy to explain how we handle personally identifiable information collected from merchants who use PayTrace's services. As the PayTrace services evolve, we may revise this policy, so please check back frequently. If you have questions about PayTrace's privacy policy please contact us at [support@PayTrace.com](mailto:support@PayTrace.com)

### Scope of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes PayTrace's treatment of personally identifiable information collected from merchants (hereafter "merchant" or "you") who use PayTrace's services, as well as consumer information that we acquire in the course of our business. This Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that PayTrace does not own or control, or to people that PayTrace does not employ or manage. 

### Information Collection and Use

PayTrace collects personally identifiable information when you register for a PayTrace account, and when you use certain PayTrace products and services. When you register with PayTrace, we ask for your contact information (such as your name, street address and email address), as well as certain information pertaining to your business, along with billing information such as your bank account number. In the course of processing a payment transaction, we typically receive from the merchant or a financial institution information related to the transaction. This normally includes information about the payment that a consumer has furnished the merchant or financial institution in placing the order. We do not acquire any information directly from consumers through the PayTrace Web site. The personally identifiable information we acquire in processing payment transactions varies according to the nature of the transaction and the way in which merchants or financial institutions are using our payment services. It may include, for example, the amount of the transaction, the consumer's name, credit card number and expiration date, billing address, and shipping address. PayTrace uses the information collected to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, to process payment transactions, to facilitate billing, and otherwise deliver the payment processing services. We may also send merchants service announcements, newsletters, and periodic notices about specials and new products. Personally identifiable consumer information is used to process payment transactions and for no other purpose. PayTrace does not offer services or sell products to children. PayTrace does not request or knowingly collect personally identifiable contact information from anyone under the age of 13. 

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Protecting personally identifiable information about merchants and consumers is an important part of our business. We share and disclose such information only as described below. PayTrace will only send personally identifiable information about you to other companies or people when: 1) we have your consent to share the information; 2) we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested. Personally identifiable consumer information is shared with third parties (such as banks and credit card processors) to the extent necessary for PayTrace to deliver payment processing services. We also may release personally identifiable information when we believe release is appropriate to: comply with law; enforce or apply our Merchant Agreement and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of PayTrace, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and risk reduction. In the unlikely event that PayTrace is acquired, merchant account information may be one of the transferred assets. 

### Cookies

PayTrace uses session cookies containing encrypted information to allow the system to uniquely identify you while you are logged in. This information allows PayTrace to process your online transactions and requests. Session cookies help us make sure you are who you say you are and are required in order to use the PayTrace shopping cart. Standing alone, cookies do not identify you personally. They merely recognize your browser. Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. 

### Information Security

Information security is critical to our business. We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We store information gathered on secure computers located in a locked data center. The number of employees involved in the management of the data center that have physical access to these computers is limited. We use firewalls and other security technology to prevent our computers from being accessed by unauthorized persons. We also require that any personally identifiable consumer information sent to us by you be encrypted using SSL encryption. To learn more about SSL, go to: <http://webopedia.internet.com/TERM/S/SSL.html>. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your Login ID/password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer and otherwise protect the password used to access the PayTrace services. 

### Account Information

PayTrace gives you the ability to edit your some of your PayTrace Account Information and preferences. Once you log into your account, you may make such changes through the Account Management menu. 

### US Location

PayTrace is located in the United States. Any information that you provide to PayTrace will be transferred to the United States. By providing personal information to us, you are consenting to its storage and use as described herein. 

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

PayTrace reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason. If there are material changes to this statement or in how PayTrace will use personally identifiable information, PayTrace will post notice on the PayTrace homepage at https://PayTrace.com prior to implementing the change. If you have additional questions about this Policy, please contact us at [support@PayTrace.com](mailto:support@PayTrace.com). 

* * *

Last revised January 2010. **PayTrace, Inc**. All right reserved.
